well well well what have we got here I
don't believe it welcome back to another
episode of Herbert craft this is getting
insane good times with scar has outdone
himself really really outdone himself so
he's breached the gap between his
floating island and the ground by well
sprouting a Jack in the Beanstalk style
plan it's now being held up by a plant
which is like the opposite of futuristic
this is fantasy like and not only that
he's built a laser on top of his build
like this and it is pretty cool-looking
and he's shooting a laser over to Mike
he's knocked off the top of my base he's
not dead he's knocked off the top that
would mean I can even tell just by
standing here that this is way taller
than my base that my house look at this
oh no it's burnt it off completely he's
only taken off like 20 blocks but that
has made him now a king of the build off
this is not good everyone this is not
good at all and oh that there's there it
is he's not he's knocked it off with a
laser beam and it's flown off and landed
in my farm look at this look at this
there it is that's exactly how I built
it as well this is the attention to
detail that I like it's not just
vanished it's it's flown off and ended
up right here in the farm but I'm afraid
retaliation is going to have to wait
don't worry I know exactly what I'm
going to do for a start I'm gonna have
to build my house even taller like up to
here and I think we need to stop scar
from building up even further but that
retaliation is
going to have to happen a little bit
later on in the episode because today
has something a little bit more
important than who has the biggest house
you can see online s cow and Mambo are
on at the moment and that's because
today's the big day it is time to open
Sahara note for real it's going to be
opening and we've been preparing all day
for it so let's quickly head back to the
main island and set up this huge grand
opening that we want to do most
everything is ready for the grand
opening
except oh just a couple of very minor
things well we don't want to just open
up this ribbon and that's it well I
actually have got here a couple of
things that are going to help us so I've
got some fireworks and I've got some
dispensers now the plan here is we're
gonna have a big button that we're gonna
press the ribbon is going to be cut and
then all of these dispensers are gonna
fire off some rockets in a really big
way so if I place down quite a few
dispensers just in front of Sahara if
I'm standing here loads of fireworks
should go off and it should be really
really impressive this may also just lag
the whole thing out well anyway I'm
gonna get this sorted I'm gonna load
this up with a bunch of fireworks and
then we will be ready to open it and I
mean it this time
we're really gonna open today is the day
I mean we've been talking about this for
weeks and weeks and weeks and we still
weren't ready even today we've been
spending hours trying to sort everything
out but I think everything is ready to
go
Sahara can officially open I gotta say I
really like I really like to think
because we've been I've been looking
through the redstone I've been trying to
fix up things last-minute there's been
some redstone was solid I thought the
red stove is not that it was great
fantastic no it's brilliant yeah no
serious bugs at all now this is a nice
tent
well okay let's hope that this works
because once it's open there's no going
back we'll have customers and that will
be that
yeah all right first impressions we've
set we've set it up it's got a ribbon
shall I shall I load it up and we'll go
yeah prepared a little bit of a exciting
opportunity do I count down with me
okay yeah okay three three two one one
go there's no no stop it stop it okay
okay again never happened three yeah two
two two
[Music]
oh my goodness
this is better yes
[Laughter]
guys you're right that hurt thank you
for four days boys this naughty treat
your customers oh my goodness just give
us a second while we fix the door
modern design and art right there okay
so according to the redstone experts
this works there's even signs now saying
what's going on yum damn but I think we
need a little bit of a presentation
first you know it's a big opening got to
make it work and looks like there's a
big audience here today right for this
yeah this is the wrong way oh yeah they
seem interested I knew these green heads
yes I'm in handy one other one as well
wandering trader in here
lovely crap away are you standing up
here where you this is this is like my
stage is up here guys stage is up here
oh I see what have you on your face that
glasses what is that thing it's oh oh I
can't see without my glasses
okay I've got a whole speech prepared
for this so you ready okay yeah all
right that what a what a beautiful crowd
I gotta say what a beautiful crowd all
right so this is a day that we've been
looking forward to for about five and a
half months Sahara is more than a
no more will consumers have to move
between shops and click several items
just to purchase things I'd also like to
bring up our tech manager who's going to
explain a few things about this amazing
system mr. Mikoto
for you to come up here tell us how this
works in as few words as possible
well grain so to start off with yeah
this has been a massive massive
technical challenge absolutely enormous
technical challenge that I have taken on
with with a scale 85 and it's been you
know it all started off with the the
item input systems the warehouse the
modules the the shifting of the items
around we needed to do a lot of block
storage decoders encoders item
transportation and we had to do a lot of
yeah there was a lot of with our
patented delivery system we can supply
high-value items at a competitive price
instantly within 30 seconds me and my
tech team have brought you innovation
with determination to form
desertification ladies and gentlemen
shop at Sahara and I would like well I
mean there's no round of applause you
know I would really like to get a
volunteer from the audience to shop at
Sahara be the very first customer and so
you're the only real person here and I'm
afraid it's gonna have to be you yeah
yeah yeah come on Bren get over here
over here over here yeah yeah yeah it is
very intuitive and you should absolutely
immediately know what to do we shouldn't
even I opened this yeah yeah and then
yeah and then ooh that's yeah I need all
of that can i yes are we gonna do a
small order to start off with would that
be wise yeah maybe just one first
I mean so just press Q on any item you
want to buy
okay Oh cute yep okay okay it's been
received
okay do you guys copy or something
because I you know get across onto that
so that's in working prayer maybe by you
know good customer feedback but look at
the lights go on ding ding we're on to
lights now how exciting is this red okay
so yes pretty exciting no no the order
hasn't been sent oh yeah yeah yeah yeah
breast button yeah okay that's correct I
gotta press the button ooh I get to push
a button no no this button here
this won't mine there's no instructions
for him what I do there we go I don't
even know what he has to do
did you have a second for children that
they could play while we wait the button
Ren okay yes all right there we go
buttons been pushed is your Winston
Bruce girl hmm as your I no I don't
think so I'm closing the company when
we're done
Sahar is over bye everyone speech for
nothing
Oh front oh where is it I got a beacon
receipt it works let's go nice wait hang
on okay I got the receipt basically
nothing was working as it should yeah
when you shop at Sahara it comes with me
here who has to break in will be open
next week for real
I'm still waiting for my croissant can I
get a like a huddle with my tech yeah
okay for a second okay shall we kill
zone customer customer okay here's my
idea we kill him okay we bury him get
rid of him make him disappear we have
enough money we're fine okay we do that
yeah we realized Cassie
nobody saw this yeah I think that sounds
a bit harsh to be honest he's a good guy
think about think about his think think
about his think about his sunglasses I
haven't I haven't thought about it since
he arrived actually I mean to be fair
guys fix the redstone and then we have a
real shop well I see I don't think he's
gonna be complaining because I missed
price the beacons he just bought a
beacon for one diamond they're supposed
to be $10 hmm that's pretty good price
[Music]
the TMT the explosion of the front
yeah him look he's interested look he's
still look at him I think you're waiting
for his products this product yeah where
we put the payment chest terribly yes
hold on he's ordered something but we
don't have any more might we don't have
any more minecarts - I only put one
minecart in I wasn't expecting to all
this much weeds and clothes and get this
working
[Laughter]
somehow structions still you took it I
hate my life
bye we'll be right back to fix this shop
well we'll say a little bit of a
research to find what was wrong but
there mmm was it one of you guys found
it we found the error well you know hmm
it was no one's fault in particular so
touch the system again okay okay okay
but you know things like this do happen
and I think no one is to blame so I
think what we should do is go with
Sahara be beta until we're sure that all
of the potatoes that I am the bugs are
ironed out so shall we do a another
grand opening because yeah the first one
didn't go quite to plan so Ren who was
originally in our queue has taken all
right so grand opening mark to Sahara
beta yep yep
[Music]
[Laughter]
amazing
[Music]
[Applause]
Jimmy now you should be safe
yeah it should be fine great we did it
we did it now does the shot for four
days all right yeah you're the second
customer dude some instructions this
time so if you just follow those okay
you should all work so we need to just
stand back and gentleman I actually
genuinely need some beacons and some
stuff which is why I've been queuing so
I'm happy to make some purchases over
here let's take some of that and I
definitely need some of those and some
of those beautiful yep okay okay don't
say anything boys all right
waiting for customer to confirm okay
mm-hm
wait for the third light and hit confirm
button ooh okay there's actually
instructions I'm so nervous
is exploding Boop
confess okay good okay
all right I'm gonna I'm gonna just turn
around okay I don't have a yeah it takes
a while to process this is this is a
really complicated syscall earthy
quality control quality reassurance yes
I got my rockets that's I ordered some
Rockets so dang great I got the carrots
uh guys this is terrible noise his I
think his carrots went into the machine
yeah I think he got them no I did it the
cutter machine guys
come on receipts one diamond for the
carats one diamond for the Rockets one
diamond for the beacon I think everyone
deserves except Wren dog a pat on the
back because yeah yeah this is
absolutely insane this is the most
complicated thing I've ever been apart
of and I didn't do anything complicated
so I feel yeah I think I think I mean it
has been genuinely it's been a nightmare
of a project it has also been very very
interesting it's been so cool to try and
solve all of the problems and I do feel
incredibly proud that we've managed to
pull off because this is not only my
Provost now we have upgrades to do we
have now carrots to dislodge we've got
to get more stock more customers and
more diamonds and that's gonna take a
lot of work yeah yeah so dude did red
ever pay no okay okay that's not beating
up your speaking discount for first
customer
no absolutely not we made some diamonds
yeah we broke it no we definitely
haven't yet done that yet so just about
everything went wrong that could have
gone wrong with the grand opening but I
tell you what it was an extraordinarily
fun day I spent the whole day for a
morning up until this very video went
out with mumbo andis cows sorting out
Sahara and it has been a very fun
project but like I said it's not over
there's still a lot to do obviously this
is now just the beta we haven't even
gotten to full release and let me tell
you why it's the beta one the shop isn't
completely free of bugs as
so this is a very small amount of stock
we sell sand some redstone some ice some
rockets and some golden carats we want
to increase our stock so that you can
purchase anything from anything in this
chest and we want it to be able to cope
with bigger orders we want it to be more
responsive so when you click this button
you get more feedback there's so many
things to improve and I mean it's so
many things to improve to make Sahara
the place to go when you want items it's
a really really big deal but I got to
say there is absolutely nothing like
this that exists and it's very easy to
like laugh at how it kind of fell apart
when we tested it but you have to
remember that this is a very complicated
machine in Minecraft this is asking a
shop to do everything that Sahara does
is a very very complicated task I think
that minecart is going round because it
doesn't know what to do so obviously
we've got a few things to work out
however they will be sorted out in the
next couple of days Sahara is remaining
open this front door will remain open
and now we have to spend the time
getting people to go to the shop and
actually start purchasing things I can't
believe we've got to this stage it was
such like a teary moment for me having
all the fireworks go up and the grand
opening look as good as it did I'm very
very happy and I'm not surprised that
everything broke the first time but we
proved that it does work indeed it can
work it does work and it will work even
more in the future now I did say that we
would work on the village later on in
the episode however the issues with
Sahara left mumbo escale and I working
all day to get it working so I've
unfortunately totally run out of time to
do anything in regards to this but don't
worry I promise the first thing that
we're going to do in the next episode is
take this to the next level we're gonna
be back on top we're gonna build this
house higher and we're gonna stop
whatever is going on over here
we're gonna make scar regret using this
laser it is absolutely hilarious a
massive congratulations to scar this is
so this looks so cool I'm very happy
with the way things are going I can't
wait to see how insane this thing ends
up well I'm afraid that's it for me
everyone thank you very much for
watching and good bye
or well I should just say thank you very
much watching and Shop and Sahara